Ra'Fat A. AL-Msie'Deen

Curriculum Vitae



R.O. Box 61710, Mu'tah University, Alkarak - Jordan

00962795423410

✓ rafatals3ode@gmail.com

https://rafat66.github.io/Al-Msie-Deen/

in Linkedin

RafatALs3ode

PERSONAL DETAILS

Full Name Ra'fat Ahmad Ali AL–Msie'Deen

Place O.B Tafila – Jordan Nationality Jordanian

RESUME

My name is Ra'Fat Al-Msie'Deen and I am an Associate Professor at the faculty of information technology in the department of software engineering at the Mutah University, Al Karak – Jordan. I received my PhD in software engineering from the University of Montpellier 2, Montpellier – France, in 2014. I received my Master's degree in Information Technology from University Utara Malaysia, Kedah – Malaysia, in 2009. I got my B.Sc. in Computer Science from Al-Hussein Bin Talal University, Ma'an – Jordan, in 2007. I have several publications in international journals, conferences and books. I taught several courses in computer science and supervised several B.Sc. students.

PHD DISSERTATION

Reverse Engineering Feature Models From Software Variants to Build Software Product Lines: RIVEPLINE Approach. (University of Montpellier, Montpellier - France)

MASTER THESIS

A Requirement Model of Local News WEB/ WAP Application for Rural Communities. (University Utara Malaysia, Kedah — Malaysia)

SCHOLARSHIPS

A scholarship by the JOSYLEEN PROJECT - ERASMUS MUNDUS ACTION 2 towards PhD in computer science during the period of 2012-2014, Montpellier - France

ACADEMIC REFEREE

Marianne HUCHARD Universitè de Montpellier @ Montpellier - France.
Wan OSMAN Universiti Utara Malaysia @ Kedah - Malaysia.
Christelle URTADO LGI2P/Ecole des Mines d'Alès @ Nîmes - France.

EDUCATION

PhD in Computer Science

June, 2014

 $University\ of\ Montpellier,\ Montpellier\ -\ France$

Specialization: Software Engineering

TOPICS: Software Engineering and Software Product Line Engineering

Master of Science – Information Technology

March, 2009

University Utara Malaysia, Kedah - Malaysia

GPA: 3.85/4

TOPICS: Systems Analysis and Design, Database, Mobile Programming, Java Language, ...

Bachelor of Computer Science

September, 2007

Al-Hussein Bin Talal University, Ma'an – Jordan

GPA: 72.94%

The General Secondary Education Certificate

August, 2004

Grandel Secondary School, Tafila - Jordan

Scientific Stream GPA: 76.9%

MANAGERIAL EXPERIENCE

Head of the Department of CS

September, 2020 - September, 2021

Head of the Department of Computer Science, Faculty of Information Technology at Mutah University.

ACADEMIC AND TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Associate Professor

September, 2019 - present

Mutah University, Karak - Jordan

Taught Courses: Bachelor and Master Levels

<u>Bachelor level</u>: Requirements Engineering, Software Documentation, Software Architecture and Design, and Graduation Project.

Master Level: Advanced Software Engineering.

Assistant Professor

September, 2014 - September, 2019

Mutah University, Karak - Jordan

🗘 Taught Courses: Bachelor Level

Software Engineering, Computer Organization and Design, Introduction to Information Technology, Operating Systems, Database Systems, Decision Support Systems, E-Commerce Programming, Internet Programming, Special Topics In Computer Science, Computer Skills (I), Communication Skills, Computer skills (II) - Visual Basic, Algorithms, Systems Analysis and Design, Theory of Computation, Logic Circuits Design, and Graduation Project.

Full-Time Lecturer

March, 2009 – December, 2011

Tafila Technical University, Tafila - Jordan

🖒 Taught Courses: Bachelor Level

Computer Graphics, Logic Circuits Design, Computer Skills (1), Computer Skills (2), International Computer Driving License "ICDL", Java Language, C++ Language, Database, Information Retrieval Systems, Management Information Systems, Internet Programming, Systems Analysis and Design, Multimedia Systems, Software Project Management, and Graduation project.

Part-Time Lecturer

September, 2010 – June, 2011

The University of Jordan - Arabian Education and Training Group, Amman - Jordan

Program Name: "High Diploma in Information and Communication Technologies in Education ICTE"

Taught Courses:

Web Design, Graphical Design, and Graduation project.

Member of the MaREL team

January, 2012 – April, 2014

Models and Reuse Engineering Languages Team

MaREL @ Lirmm - Universitè de Montpellier, Montpellier - France

Committee Member July 1-5, 2013

Member of the organization committee for the ECOOP, ECSA and ECMFA conferences

Three conferences have been organized in Montpellier – France

Teacher of Computer Science

October, 2007 – February, 2008

Ministry of Education, Tafila - Jordan

I have taught computer science in primary and secondary schools

SKILLS

Languages Arabic (mother tongue)

English (reading, writing and conversation)

SOFTWARE MATLAB, LATEX, DIRECTOR, DREAM WEAVER, PHOTOSHOP

CERTIFICATES International Computer Driving Licence (ICDL: UN07097892)

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES Java, Python, C++, HTML, Java Script, Oracle, ASP.NET, PHP

Modeling UML

RESEARCH INTEREST

My research is primarily concerned with software engineering. In particular, my interests include:

- Software Product Line Engineering (SPLE).
- **2** Formal Concept Analysis (FCA).
- **3** Software Documentation.
- Software Visualization.
- **6** Software Comprehension.

PUBLICATIONS

Journal:

- [1] R. Al-Msie'deen, and A. Blasi, "Software Evolution Understanding: Automatic Extraction of Software Identifiers Map for Object-Oriented Software Systems," *Journal of Communications Software and Systems*, vol. 17, no. 1, pp. 20–28, 2021.
- [2] R. Al-Msie'deen, "Tag Clouds for Software Documents Visualization," *International Journal on Informatics Visualization*, vol. 3, no. 4, pp. 361–364, 2019.
- [3] R. Al-Msie'deen, "Tag Clouds for Object-Oriented Source Code Visualization," Engineering, Technology & Applied Science Research, vol. 9, no. 3, pp. 4243–4248, 2019.
- [4] Mohammed Alsuwaiket, A. Blasi, and R. Al-Msie'deen, "Formulating Module Assessment for Improved Academic Performance Predictability in Higher Education," *Engineering, Technology & Applied Science Research*, vol. 9, no. 3, pp. 4287–4291, 2019.
- [5] R. Al-Msie'deen, and A. Blasi, "Supporting software documentation with source code summarization," *International Journal of Advanced and Applied Sciences*, vol. 6, no. 1, pp. 59–67, 2019.
- [6] R. Al-Msie'deen, and A. Blasi, "The Impact of the Object-Oriented Software Evolution on Software Metrics: The Iris Approach," *Indian Journal of Science and Technology*, vol. 11, no. 8, pp. 1–8, 2018.
- [7] R. Al-Msie'deen, "Automatic labeling of the object-oriented source code: The Lotus approach," Science International-Lahore, vol. 30, no. 1, pp. 45–48, 2018.
- [8] R. Al-Msie'deen, "Visualizing object-oriented software for understanding and documentation," *International Journal of Computer Science and Information Security*, vol. 13, no. 5, pp. 18–27, 2015.
- [9] R. Al-Msie'deen, M. Huchard, A. Seriai, C. Urtado, and S. Vauttier, "Automatic documentation of [mined] feature implementations from source code elements and use-case diagrams with the REVPLINE approach," *International Journal of Software Engineering and Knowledge Engineering*, vol. 24, no. 10, pp. 1413–1438, 2014.
- [10] A. M. Frijat and R. Al-Msie'deen "A requirement model of local news wap/web application for rural community," Advances in Computer Science and Engineering, vol. 4, no. 1, pp. 37–53, 2010.

Book:

- [1] R. Al-Msie'deen, Object-oriented Software Documentation. Lambert Academic Publishing, 2019.
- [2] <u>R. Al-Msie'deen</u>, A. Seriai, and M. Huchard, *Reengineering Software Product Variants Into Software Product Line: REVPLINE Approach*. Lambert Academic Publishing, 2014.
- [3] R. Al-Msie'deen, A Requirement Model of Local News Application for Rural Communities: A New Model for Rural News. Lambert Academic Publishing, 2014.
- [4] R. Al-Msie'deen, M. Huchard, and C. Urtado, Reverse Engineering Feature Models. Lambert Academic Publishing, 2014.

[5] R. Al-Msie'deen, Feature Location in a Collection of Software Product Variants. Lambert Academic Publishing, 2014.

International Conference:

- [1] R. Al-Msie'deen, M. Huchard, A. Seriai, C. Urtado, and S. Vauttier, "Reverse engineering feature models from software configurations using formal concept analysis," in *Proceedings of the Eleventh International Conference on Concept Lattices and Their Applications, Košice, Slovakia, October 7-10, 2014.*, ser. CEUR Workshop Proceedings, K. Bertet and S. Rudolph, Eds., vol. 1252. CEUR-WS.org, 2014, pp. 95–106.
- [2] R. Al-Msie'deen, A. Seriai, M. Huchard, C. Urtado, and S. Vauttier, "Documenting the mined feature implementations from the object-oriented source code of a collection of software product variants," in *The 26th International Conference on Software Engineering and Knowledge Engineering, Hyatt Regency, Vancouver, BC, Canada, July 1-3, 2013.*, M. Reformat, Ed. Knowledge Systems Institute Graduate School, 2014, pp. 138–143.
- [3] R. Al-Msie'deen, A. Seriai, M. Huchard, C. Urtado, S. Vauttier, and H. E. Salman, "Feature location in a collection of software product variants using formal concept analysis," in *Safe and Secure Software Reuse 13th International Conference on Software Reuse, ICSR 2013, Pisa, Italy, June 18-20. Proceedings*, ser. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, J. M. Favaro and M. Morisio, Eds., vol. 7925. Springer, 2013, pp. 302–307.
- [4] R. Al-Msie'deen, A. Seriai, M. Huchard, C. Urtado, and S. Vauttier, "Mining features from the object-oriented source code of software variants by combining lexical and structural similarity," in *IEEE 14th International Conference on Information Reuse & Integration, IRI 2013, San Francisco, CA, USA, August 14-16, 2013.* IEEE, 2013, pp. 586–593.
- [5] R. Al-Msie'deen, A. Seriai, M. Huchard, C. Urtado, S. Vauttier, and H. E. Salman, "Mining features from the object-oriented source code of a collection of software variants using formal concept analysis and latent semantic indexing," in *The 25th International Conference on Software Engineering and Knowledge Engineering, Boston, MA, USA, June 27-29, 2013.* Knowledge Systems Institute Graduate School, 2013, pp. 244–249.
- [6] R. Al-Msie'deen, M. Huchard, A. D. Seriai, C. Urtado, S. Vauttier, and A. Al-Khlifat, "Concept lattices: A representation space to structure software variability," in *Information and Communication* Systems (ICICS), 2014 5th International Conference on, Irbid, Jordan, April 2014, pp. 1–6.

International Workshop:

- [1] R. Al-Msie'deen, A. D. Seriai, M. Huchard, C. Urtado, S. Vauttier, and H. E. Salman, "An approach to recover feature models from object-oriented source code," in *Actes de la Journée Lignes de Produits 2012*, Lille, France, Novembre 2012, pp. 15–26.
- [2] R. Al-Msie'deen, A. D. Seriai, M. Huchard, C. Urtado, S. Vauttier, and H. E. Salman, "Feature mining from a collection of software product variants," in *Actes de la Journées GDR GPL CIEL AFADL 2013*, Nancy, France, April 2013, pp. 1–2.

- [3] H. E. Salman, A. Seriai, C. Dony, and <u>R. Al-Msie'deen</u>, "Recovering traceability links between feature models and source code of product variants," in *Proceedings of the VARiability for You Workshop: Variability Modeling Made Useful for Everyone*, ser. VARY '12. New York, NY, USA: ACM, 2012, pp. 21–25.
- [4] H. E. Salman, A. Seriai, C. Dony, and R. Al-Msie'deen, "Identifying traceability links between product variants and their features," in *REVE'2013: 1st International workshop on Reverse Variability Engineering*, 2013, pp. 17–23.
- [5] H. E. Salman, A. Seriai, C. Dony, and <u>R. Al-Msie'deen</u>, "Genetic algorithms as recovering traceability links method between feature models and source code of product variants," in *Actes de la Journée Lignes de Produits 2012*, Lille, France, Novembre 2012, pp. 3–14.

Poster:

[1] R. Al-Msie'deen, A. Seriai, M. Huchard, C. Urtado, S. Vauttier, and H. E. Salman, "A methodology to recover feature models from object-oriented source code," Innsbruck, Austria, September 2012.

Doctoral Symposium:

[1] R. Al-Msie'deen, "Mining feature models from the object-oriented source code of a collection of software product variants," in *Doctoral Symposium of ECOOP'13*, Montpellier, France, July 2013, pp. 1–10.